# （福建·福州）
(Fuzhou, Fujian)
# 现在才是六点钟
It's just 6am
# 但是马路上的人真的是特别多
However, there's a lot of people on the street already
# 我们今天到怎么繁忙的地方来
Today, we came to such a busy place
# 就是为了来吃一碗锅边糊
just to enjoy a bowl of "guobianhu" ("wok edge slurry")
# 如果你和我一样
If you heard this name
# 也是第一次听到这个名字
for the first time in your life like me
(aka "guobian" or "wok edge")
# 真的会有点摸不着头脑
you might really get puzzled
# 不过肯定的是
Anyway, it seems obvious that
# 它的制作和锅边有关
the process has something to do with the wok edge
# （米浆）
(Rice slurry)
# （这么潇洒的姿势 再来一遍）
Such graceful technique, let's see it again
# 这个是我们要的3块5的锅边
We ordered this guobian for 3.5 yuan
# 然后配上了三角糕和油饼来吃
and will have it with this "sanjiaogao" ("triangular cake") and "youbing" ("oil-fried cake")
# （来这家店吃饭）就是你没坐下 大叔就会帮你端上来这碗锅边
At this restaurant, the uncle serves you a bowl of guobian even before you sit down
# 然后自己去拿油饼或者三角糕什么的
Then you go to take the side dish like youbing, sanjiaogao by yourself.
# （油饼 三角糕 锅边）
Left: youbing ("oil-fried cake")
Middle: sanjiaogao ("triangular cake")
Right: guobian ("wok edge")
# 锅边糊做的时候 是把
This guobianhu is made by
# 米浆沿着锅沿倒下去
pouring rice slurry along the wok edge
# 等它差不多半熟的时候
When it's halfway cooked
# 刮进汤里
and then scape it into the soup
# 这碗锅边糊 你能看到的是
Then what you can see is
# 上面是汤 下面是米浆块
soup on the top, covering the rice slurry pieces
# 里面还有鱿鱼 虾米
There's also squid and shrimps inside
# 撒了一些紫菜 还有一些葱花
together with nori and chopped scallion
# 这样就出锅了
Then it's served
# 这个汤很像
This soup pretty much looks like
# 虾米和鱿鱼熬出来的汤
a stew of shrimps and squid
# 表面泛着一些零星的油花
with a pinch of oil floating on top
# 下面米浆块是很多的
There're many rice slurry pieces underneath
# 可能是因为它（米浆块）太滑嫩
As they (rice slurry pieces) are probably too tender and smooth
# 以至于想把它夹起来
even picking them up with chopsticks
# 都有点困难
appears to be a difficult task
# （算了 还是直接用勺吧）
(Forget it. Just use a spoon)
# 来这家小店吃饭 并没有很多的选择
There are not that many options at this small restaurant
# 除了人手一碗的锅边糊
Besides a bowl of guobianhu that everyone takes
# 也就是炸米糕 油饼这些了
there are only things like "zhamigao" ("fried rice cakes") and "youbing" ("oil-fried cakes")
# 有没有发现
Have you ever realized that
# 大家在早上起来
you are especially tolerant to deep fried food
# 对油炸的东西 格外的宽容
as you wake up in the early morning
# 米糕
"Migao" ("rice cake")
# 就是米糕 炸的米糕 五香味
It's just a rice cake, deep fried with the 5-spices flavor
# 早上起来和我们共进早餐的
Those who enjoy breakfast with us in the early morning
# 永远是起得早的老年人
are always those elderlies who wake up early
# （老年人之友）
( ↑ Friend to the elderlies)
# （关 注 雪 鱼 探 店）
(Subscribe)